> > Jem Young: 嗯，你知道我们没做什么吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Mm,
you know what we haven't done?
这只是一个侧面的探索。
And this is a bit of a side quest.
但我们在一段时间内没有查看过我们的行动日志。
But we haven't looked at
our op log in a while.
让我们看看发生了什么，我只想看看发生了什么。
Let's see what's going on there,
I just want to see what's happening.
向我道歉但这对我来说很有趣
Apologies for the shift, but
it's just interesting to me.
所以我们说猫的 /var/log ，然后看 authlog 和
So let's say cat /var/log and
then, look at the authlog and
就会拒绝我所以我要去上个大爆炸了
it's going to deny me, so
I'm going to sudo bang bang.
这里发生了什么
What's going on here?
有什么有趣的吗
Anything interesting?
是啊很多人都想再接我的电脑了
Yeah, it's a lot of people trying
to connect to my computer again.
一会儿好吗
Later, yes?
>> 扬声器 2: 我注意到您正在使用历史记录快捷方式，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I noticed you're
using the history shortcut,
你没提过
you haven't mentioned that.
>> Jem Young: 历史捷径，我昨天没有吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: The history shortcut,
did I not yesterday?
嗯，历史的捷径，所以你可以上去，你就是在横动。
Hmm, the history shortcut, so
you can go up, and you're just traversing.
>> 演讲者 2: 砰。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Bang bang.
>> 扬声器 3: 对，伪砰砰。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Yeah, the pseudo bang bang.
>> Jem Young: 我昨天说过，嗯。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I mentioned that yesterday,
yeah.
只是以防你不知道
Just in case you didn't know.
如果您想运行最后一个命令，那么
If you wanna run the last command, so
我要再跑一次那也没用
I'm gonna run this again,
which won't work without sudo.
但如果我跑出了苏多就会重演我想要的
But if I run sudo bang it's
gonna replay what I want and
它将会看到最后的指令
it's gonna see the last command but
with sudo.
所以我们只是用 sudo 命令来重播历史，然后再继续工作。
So we're just replaying the history with
the sudo command and then it works again.
如果你没发现
If you didn't catch that,
这会给你节省很多时间
that is something that will
save you a lot of time.
另一个我做的就是倒掉我的巴什历史，所以我可以上去了。
The other one I did was reversing my
bash history, so I can go up, down.
如果你想在你的巴什历史上找到一些东西，控制 R，说日志和
If you wanna find something in your
bash history, control R, say log and
它将会看到你们的所有历史
it will look through all
of your bash history.
这些都是非常有用的。
These are super useful.
他们是很棒的捷径
They're nice shortcuts.
而且好处是他们也在你的 Mac 电脑上工作如果你做了很多指令
And the good thing is they work on your
Mac too, if you do a lot of command line
编程，使用控制 R，穿越历史记录。
programming, using control R,
going up through history going back.
同样，正是这个共同的平台让这些东西强大，因为，对，
Again, it's this common platform that
makes these things powerful because, yes,
而 OS X 是 BSc 我们用 Ubuntu
while OS X is a BSc and
this we're using Ubuntu,
是不同的 Linux 发行版或不同的分发版。
which is a different Linux distribution or
different distribution.
还用这个 cusz 我们还用这个共同程序的 bash
They still work the same cuz we're still
using bash which is this common program
所有这些都是有用的
that works over all of them.